## ALFI FILSAFALASAFI

# INSTRUCTOR AND DEVELOPER IT

Pasuruan | +62 852 3284 2550 | filsalasafi@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/alfi-filsafat | https://alfi-filsafalasafi.github.io/My/ | https://github.com/Alfi-Filsafalasafi

#### **SUMMARY**

I started coding in 2017. I have skills in website development (PHP Laravel), mobile (Flutter), and desktop applications. Besides coding, I also enjoy sharing knowledge. I also have experience in organizational activities. For more details, visit my website.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

#### PPPPTK BOE VEDC MALANG

Internship Desktop Developt (December 2018 – May 2019)

- Using desktop pascal dan mysql.
- Creating flowchart system.
- performing unit testing

### **ED Management**

Database Designer (March 2020 – January 2022)

- Communicating client requirements
- Creating flowchart and ERD.
- Creating database framework in SQL, and Microsoft Office

### SMKN 1 Purwosari, Pasuruan

Internship Teacher Software Engineering (January 2023 – June 2023)

- Teaching X dan XII class
- Creating teaching modules and conducting learning evaluations
- Assisting with school administration

### PT Solusi Infotech Semesta Indonesia (SIESTA)

Internship Front End Mobile (July 2023 – September 2023)

- Using flutter (GetX), firebase, and AWS
- Creating wireframe application

# **EDUCATION**

## SMKN 1 Purwosari (2017 – 2020)

Software Engineering – Grade 89

# UNIVERSITAS NEGERI MALANG (2020 – 2024)

Bachelor's Degree in Informatics Engineering Education - GPA 3,93

### **CERTIFICATION**

- Certificate of Competence: Safety, Health and Quality
- The Epson Basic Training (Basic Inkjet, Lseries, & Projector)

### **SKILLS**

- Web Developing
- Flutter (Mobile Developing)
- Database Analysis and Designer
- UI/UX Designer
- Microsoft Office
- Teach, Lead and Communications

### **ACHIEVEMENTS**

- Best Award Category (Information Technology, Multimedia, and Communication) at Universiti Malaysia Perlis, 2023.
- Gold Medal ARAU International Creativity Exhibition (ACE) at Universiti Malaysia Perlis, 2023.
- 1st Winner of Digital Learning Media Fesmaro at Departemen Teknik Elektro and Informatika UM, 2023.
- Passed the PKM-RSH Financing with the title "Smart Braille: Appropriate Application of Distance Learning During a Pandemic for the Blind" at Kemendikbudristek, 2022.
- Finalist of Musabaqah Desain Aplikasi Al-Qur'an at Universitas Negeri Yogyakarta, 2021.
- 5th Winner of IT Software Solution For Business Tk Jawa Timur at Dinas Pendidikan Provinsi Jawa Timur, 2020.
- 2nd Winner of IT Software Solution For Business Tk Wilker 2 Jawa Timur at Dinas Pendidikan Provinsi Jawa Timur, 2019.
- 2nd Winner of Reporter Giat Prestasi Penegak at Kwarcab Pasuruan, 2019.
- Finalis of Web Design Competition at STMIK ASIA MALANG with Dinas Pariwisata Kota Batu, 2019.
- Gold Medal of FWKKP effective innovation Jawa Timur and Goes to Thailand at Kwarda Jatim, 2018.
- 1st place parallel at SMPN 2 Wonorejo, 2017.
- 3rd Winner of LTTP Kabupaten Pasuruan at SMAN 1 Kejayan, 2016.
- Top 5 Sispres (Siswa Berprestasi) Kabupaten Pasuruan at Dinas Pendidikan Kabupaten Pasuruan, 2014.

## **ORGANIZATION**

- Coordinator of the LKTIN PESC UM 2023 public relations Section at Workshop Elektro 2023
- Coordinator of the LTDC UM 2022 Sponsorship Section at Workshop Elektro 2023
- Leader Team Management Gemastik and LIDM UM 2023
- Secretary of IT Division at Workshop Elektro 2022
- IT Division Project Responsible Member at Workshop Elektro 2021
- Member of Pasuruan Dev 2019-now
- Scout Leader at SMKN 1 Purwosari 2018-2019
- Member of Ethics (programming extracurricular) at SMKN 1 Purwosari 2017-2020
- Chairman of the student council at SMPN 2 Wonorejo 2016-2017

# **TEACHER**

- Teaching assistant (TA) for a course in Algorithms and Basic Computer Programming at Universitas Negeri Malang, 2024
- Internship Teacher Majoring in Software Engineering at SMKN 1 Purwosari, 2023
- Boy Scout Teacher at SMPN 2 Wonorejo, 2018-2020
- Assistant Teacher Scouts at SMPN 2 Wonorejo, 2016-2020
- Assistant Teacher Scouts at SDN Wonosari, 2017

## **SPEAKER**

- Speaker of Public Speaking and how scouting can impact my life" at Scout of SMKN 1 Purwosari 2023
- Speaker of Basic HTML at Workshop Elektro UM 2022
- Speaker of experiences from scouts who were able to go abroad at Scout of SMKN 1 Purwosari 2019